webdevelopersnotes.com 2017-10-02

# Privacy Policy

[](https://www.webdevelopersnotes.com/) [Home](https://www.webdevelopersnotes.com/ "Go to WebDevelopersNotes.") / Privacy Policy

**Dear WebDevelopersNotes.com visitors – Your privacy is important to us.**  
On this page I tell you about the information collected from you when you visit this web site and describe how it is used.

## Personal information such as name and email address

Personal information (such as name and email address) is **never collected from the site _without your consent_**. This means, you don’t need to tell us your name, contact details or _any personal information_ to browse the pages on this web site. Most pages on the site have a “feedback/comments” form through which you can ask a question or post a comment. These have fields for name and email in addition to any feedback, question or comments you may have. However, it is not mandatory for you to submit your real name or a valid email address.

Your inputs from these “feedback/comments” forms, if deemed relevant and helpful to other visitors, might be displayed on corresponding web pages with your name and the date/time the form was submitted. If you don’t want your real name to show, please enter a false name or “Anonymous” in the field.

## Log files

WebDevelopersNotes.com, like most other web sites, maintains log files of visitors on the server. These collect information such as your I.P. (Internet Protocol) address, your ISP, browser name and version along with various configurations of your system, time of your visit and how you have used this web site (such as the number of pages /files you have viewed and how you arrived at this web site).

## Links to external sites

WebDevelopersNotes.com carries links to external sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policy or content of external sites.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on WebDevelopersNotes.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing _cooking_ ads to someone who frequents _cooking_ sites).

## DoubleClick DART cookies

We also may use DART _cookies_ for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (“interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

## Non-personally identifiable information

We use third-party companies to serve ads and collect non-personally identifiable information (e.g., the pages you visit, and which links you click, which ads you see and click on, and the categories of search terms you enter) when you visit our web site. These companies may use the information outlined above (which does not include your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These companies often use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "NAI universal user opt-out") (link to the NAI universal user opt-out).

## Mailing list

Mailing list at this web site is now closed. When active, your email was collected and stored in our mailing list database (password protected) only if you request to join the mailing list. WebDevelopersNotes e-mailers carry new developments on the site and/or news in the field of web development. Each e-mailer has a Remove from mailing list option at the bottom.

In case of any questions relating to privacy, please write to the webmaster.

Many thanks to [JenSense](http://www.jensense.com/) for posting the privacy policy concerning **Cookies and Web Beacons** and **DoubleClick DART cookies**.
